once again my name is
I am a income strategist and life is a
financial adviser since 2004 if you've
not heard my radio show it's also on
every Saturday on WBT at 4 o'clock
strictly educational is that what I
truly believe as you learned throughout
this presentation as well you like to
learn about any other webinars or see
any other past webinars you can go to
Doudna at Lulu's money.com and you can
also have our YouTube channel will show
you all the past webinars we've done
since this pandemic unfortunately has
started for us and these are all
articles and places I've had published
in Forbes money fortune on sage B and
all these other ones and have been
fortunate to have articles those are all
available on our website as well and if
you've not received a copy of my book
across the bridge retirement I encourage
you it's complimentary we can give you a
hardcover copy or a PDF copy of that you
can call it in that number or email us
we mor have to get that out to you
complimentary as well insurance
companies nobody talks about out in the
read says negative things again from
positive to about insurance companies
but let's talk about the history of
insurance companies I mean the first
insurance company in the u.s. dates back
to the common old A's it's called the
Philadelphia contributor ship was
co-founded by Ben Franklin in 1752
throughout history these types of
insurance companies have expanded in
reaction to offer new risks of modern
life such as disability business and
automobiles as late 19th century various
scandals and dubious practices have
rocked the the insurance industry all
over the place so under the McKay
Furguson Act of 1945 insurance companies
are exempt from most regular regulation
are instead subject to state law and
state insurance guarantees then we're
going to cover all that through the next
25 to 30 minutes today and today the
size of Insurance errs and continues to
increase this company is merged with one
another and one other financial services
firms so a lot of the smaller insurance
companies haven't been merging with some
of the bigger ones to cover the most
important thing and believe it or not
insurance companies yes as they make a
lot of money out there at the end of the
day we need them to cover ourselves our
people our home and so forth and that's
what they're there for
so generally when you think of insurance
company if you think of oh I have auto
insurance and health insurance and
homeowners insurance and life insurance
but if you look through the next three
pages and it's amazing all the different
types of insurances are out there from
chargeback insurance credit insurance
you have flood insurance earthquake
insurance tons of different types of
insurances so it's more than just one
type of fits all as you can see here you
got kidnap and ransom insurance believe
it or not you got marine insurance you
have pet insurance which if you don't
have pets if you do like I said this has
a nice thing to have satellite insurance
so basically what I'm trying to say is
then the last let's hear terrorism
insurance travel insurance weather
insurance etc if there's which we want
to protect it there's an insurance out
there for you and they will fight it for
you
so how many insurance companies are
there really in the United States when
you think about it mm a lot of people
are thinking well there's a lot but
it'll realize how many there really are
if you look at just the United States
alone there's a little over five
thousand nine hundred sixty-five current
insurance companies out there when some
of the ones on the screen there are some
of the ones that we work with and that
are out there some of the larger ones
you may have heard of but that's a lot
of insurance companies if you break it
down to the United each state you're
looking about a little over 1,100
insurance companies per state out there
a guide for everybody so you have
internal insurance companies you have
large corporation service companies so
in that one insurance company covers
everything it's not a one-size-fits-all
scenario so we have the insurance
companies so who regulates insurance
company over an nei then ACI is the
national associations of insurance
companies they're the ones who over look
all the insurance companies like the
government that overlooks the federal
and federal overlooks the government and
so forth every state out there has their
own insurance guarantee Association
which is under the national associations
of interest company for instance North
Carolina if you wanted to search what
their their guidelines are they're
covered by the North Carolina life and
health guarantee Association most every
state out there has the same beginning
for ending life and health guarantee
Association like South Carolina Georgia
and so forth so they're all covered and
insured through that part of it so when
it comes to insurance coverage it's like
what is the right coverage for you you
hear some of these commercials out there
like Liberty Mutual and they give you
the right coverage and State Farm and
Allstate our hands are for you or our
that their phrases are so with so many
options how do you know which ones to
write on the coverage because once again
every insurance company is run
differently per se with their way that
they add things into their portfolio and
add things to policyholders so finally
the right coverage for yourself
sometimes can be confusing as well so
when you're looking into it you want to
realize it's like okay am i talking to
an independent agent
or am I talking to a captive agent and
this is a very important thing when
you're shopping around it's like if
you're looking for a car you can just go
to a Ford dealership or a Chevy
dealership well those are like those are
captive dealerships and if you go to a
Ford dealership you're probably not
going to find a Mercedes Benz and if you
go to a Mercedes dealership you're
probably not going to find it for but if
you go to a general place you're going
to find a little bit of all of them like
cars calm you'll find all the different
options out there for you I mean
independent agents they are partnered
with multiple different insurance
companies they can offer multiple
options and different products and from
all the different companies and they
make comparison shopping easier let me
use like the car analogy like you go to
car comm and pick out your own car and
so they're just going to one place or
captive agents they generally sell
policies from only the insurance
companies or their line of options that
they're allowed to sell from so makes
that sometimes their product options are
limited and some of them may even
unfortunately push their sales based on
quotas so when you're looking at an
independent agent versus captive agent
very important I am an independent agent
my company's an infinite agent all the
agents that work for me are independent
agents is that allows us to work with
over of generally we work with about 56
different companies right now versus
some people out there they work with one
or two so there's there's the right
there's a big pro and a con for
insurance out there alone because some
captive agents might have what you're
looking for but they might not which
could make it a con or independent
agents have the general ability they
have no loyalty to one person over
another so let's look at the types of
insurances that are out there and the
pros and cons of each one of them now
one of the biggest feared insurance is
out there that people are weary of it's
called long term care insurance I mean
the pros on it it protects the people
you care about the most it gives you the
financial protection to provide cash
flow to pay for services if needed you
have flexible benefit options premiums
potentially are tax deductible for
individual and businesses then options
available for return of premium on
traditional long term care insurance and
covers you in case of an emergency
is long-term care policies premiums they
could increase over time they could
select an appropriate policy is
delivered for that care that you get you
get the wrong care once again you need
home care assisted living or special
needs if you don't get the right care
long-term care coverage could be that
detrimental to you you may never use it
and generally it's very costly and
expensive Wimmer to get policies for you
but there are alternatives out there if
you look for the right one again working
with independent agents to shop the
different kinds of long-term care
insurance will get the covers that you
need more than the coverage that they
want to sell you we all been down the
road of health insurance it's probably
one of the most confusing ones out there
as far as what should health service
well what's the difference between what
ethnic and cover versus United
Healthcare and Blue Cross Blue Shield
with this excuse me because there's
multiple types of coverage available
individual group short term and so forth
so you have very lot of options out
there it gives you protection from
financial exposure and you get
discounted costs and provider services
based on your contract rates and under
the HH and income area they have
affordable premiums based on your income
so they can generalize health insurance
to your lifestyle to how much your cost
now of course the cons are is it can be
expensive with no premium subsidy I mean
there's potentially high deductibles and
coinsurance amounts which can limited it
limited number of insurer's out there
for TAC 8 insurance limited power
networks provider networks in your area
could be available there priestess of
pre-existing conditions
sometimes they won't some insurance
companies will take you or the raise
your rates for pre conditions and then
enrollment periods when can you enroll
for health insurance like Medicare and
the Part A and Part B again it's finding
what's right for you
now the pros again for one of the
biggest things I see with insurance
insurance that covers your health it's
one of the most foremost important
things of your life so you might need to
have it covered but the con is sometimes
you get the wrong insurance and it
doesn't cover what you need down the
road the life insurance this is a this
is an optional insurance for legacy
planning it's very important personally
to cover your legacy cover your loved
ones and another big portent hardest to
me
family comes first in all situations and
so the pros it provides cash for dealing
for adverse financial consequences in an
insured person's death um just about all
of them are tax-free if you pass away
they avoid probate on the cash values
grow cash tax deferred well I'm some
will allow you to take out loans and
then be tax free think about the loans
for the insurance you can exchange life
insurance for annuities if you wanted to
exchange it with no tax consequences
whatsoever um some monthly premiums can
be a write-off if you own your own
business and some policies paid when
you're sure is still living and there's
a lot of intangibles with that as well
which are a very pro athlete for
yourself now unfortunately like again if
we go from pros to cons like an all
insurance sometimes you feel like it's a
waste of money when you never receive
the benefit fix it specifically term
insurance term insurance like you buy
20-year term you're spending X amount of
dollar dollars to cover your policy you
pass what you don't pass away you live
through it you feel like that money is
never reach double again but least you
had the security over those 20 years to
cover everybody and then this is another
one between the independent and the
captive area it's many insurance
companies with different pricing and
benefits to consider when evaluating
options it's getting the right help life
insurance for yourself but you want term
you want whole index Universal variable
universal once again doing your research
and knowing what's out there another con
would be cash surrender values or easily
less than the premiums paid over the
first several years of policy sometimes
a policy I mean may not recover the
premiums paid if the policy is
surrendered and you no longer need the
insurance
and it could be a complex process for
applying and getting approved for life
insurance again previous existing
existed conditions again what are you
looking for the life insurance to do for
yourself are you little bit looking for
it to protect yourself are you looking
for protect your house your cost and so
forth so life insurance I think is a
valuable part of the your life but you
got to find again the right life
insurance for yourself
annuities another part of the very
discretely talked about through
insurance companies a lot of people have
a lot of pros and cons to them pros
you're getting upside potential with no
downside risk now you get protection
from the market on the all grow
tax-deferred whether it's non qualified
or qualify money they can provide you a
guaranteed lifetime income that can
never outlive they do avoid probate upon
your death and they all offer guarantee
rates return now cons as annuities
aren't for everybody it's not a
one-size-fits-all early withdrawal
penalties if you take too much money out
of what they're allowing you to do and
this is the biggest one is there's so
many different options as I mentioned
earlier with captive versus independent
finding the option right for you whether
it's liquidity and you're looking for
growth if you're looking for legacy
planning or if you're looking for income
um sometimes the fee structure can be
confusing
we don't variable annuities is generally
the one that that's talked about they
have I I don't offer variable annuities
but I do have people that have them that
they have a lot of fees attached to them
that are undisclosed so if you're gonna
get an annuity make sure you know that
there's any fees if applicable the
course term limits and surrender charges
I mean you don't want to be getting a 10
year annuity if you're only going to
need the money protected for three or
four years and so making sure you know
the right one for you as well as down
there but this with all insurances every
positive can be turned into a negative
and every negative can be turned into a
positive it's all defining what is best
for yourself
life is not
sighs Fitz on the other insurance
company - why - it's off and like you
don't see these gold fishes what is
wrong with this picture well obviously
each fish is in the straw bowl so what
is right for your neighbor or right for
your family member or a friend or a
colleague doesn't necessarily make it
right or wrong for you but they said
annuities life insurance health and all
these other insurances we're talking
about just because you're your brother
John has an annuity and he doesn't like
it doesn't mean it's not right for you
and vice versa maybe you have life
insurance and you love it once doesn't
make it perfect for him as well and I I
always didn't refer to this as like you
can't go to me you can't go to
McDonald's and get a whopper if you want
to have the whopper you got to go to
Burger King if you want to have the Big
Mac you gotta go to McDonald's and said
it's not a one-size-fits-all every place
has their own little agenda atop of it
so who regulates insurance companies how
do they protected who's guiding them to
make sure that you the consumer are
taken care of and I think this is a very
important part of knowing about
insurance companies and if and what it's
right for you sorry just give a little
water the end of the day insurance
should be easy for you to research you
should be easy to get in contact and you
should easily be under understand the
coverage if you get whatever cover to
get whether it's for marine insurance
earthquake insurance annuity life
insurance any of those let the research
be done for you make sure you can be in
hold of them and make sure you
understand what the coverages in
insurance what it means for us it's it's
hard work and always be available
because again it's not a one size fits
all when you come in couples a month
might be 60 and 65 years old or might be
an individual who's 62 or 56 or 70 they
need what they need for themselves not
with their brother down the street or
the friend got the street got four and
always being available is one thing as
insurance companies they always are
available for you they're never going to
receive that sorry we're not available
for you right now we'll call you back on
Tuesday now there's never
a lot of carriers out there that focus
on each one of their own
I mean company carriers insurers or
large corporations at salad surance like
health insurance companies like United
Blue Cross and Blue Shield and Humana
they focus strictly on health insurance
life insurance companies like Lincoln
North American Prudential MassMutual
they've their biggest thing is they
focus on life insurance the property
casually like your auto insurance and
homeowners and boat or motorcycle and
liability carriers they focus on that so
if you like you you want good car
insurance you can call Geico State Farm
I'm just popping some off the top my
head that I can think about but they're
gonna focus on that type of insurance
they're not going to focus on life
insurance and like health insurance
carriers are not going to focus on like
nudies and stuff like that in life
insurance are gonna focus on health and
care so finding the right one and each
brand is very important for you and
knowing the ratings is also very
important the ratings are from different
carriers and a lot of people don't feel
comfortable with anything now and an
atan a rated company in which generally
means a lot more stability
let's see most of the agents they
represent the big companies and they may
be captive or may be independent they go
between peoples which they call manual
managing general agents which are the
intermediate between the agents and the
insurance company that helps merge the
program and underwriting it so forth for
instance I'm gonna squeeze one of the
largest companies out there help you
call Allianz they have they're an
independent company they have go-between
it's MGAs then they have the agents the
agents work through the MGAs to go
through a lens going directly to Allianz
to open up a policy and research the
policy will probably not happen you have
to go through a third person like State
Farm is the same way even though they're
captive you have to go to them in order
to find the big company so knowing that
the bigger companies have these
go-betweens
is you have more people out there
looking for your best interest then
let's just say I will talk negative
about anybody there's enough that's a
company ABC you can go directly to
company ABC and open you want
well at that point you're only getting
what they're offering you're not getting
whatever else is offering at the same
time
involves money promises risk and
predictions to protect the public every
state has a Department of Insurance
responsible for regulating insurance
within the state to keep extremely close
tabs on insurance companies states also
make laws and take to the insurer to the
court if they expect something fishy the
Department of Insurance which here at
North Carolina's were out of Raleigh is
a great thing a lot of people don't like
them that are in the insurance industry
I think they're fantastic because they
regulate to make sure everybody is doing
thing on the same level page and if
something is not done correctly they
will make sure it is done correctly
these laws and rules are designed to
make insurance companies stay
financially sound plans and policies
throughout the thoroughly explained make
sure the premiums are reisel and most
importantly they protect the
policyholder that's what these laws are
for is there are some agents that said
you wouldn't put somebody that's 85
years old in a twenty year policy
because it's not it doesn't sound
financially right at the same time you
need but they're gonna do is they're
gonna make sure that agent doesn't do
that to somebody you're not going to put
somebody who's 60 years old and as
$50,000 her name and that's all they
have and tie that up in a 1520 year when
you never but somebody that has no
family members and no like in a life
insurance policy that you have no access
to so they're there to protect you most
importantly it's very wonderful company
to have out there and they make
insurance available to everyone and this
can be a tough one the government wants
insurance companies to cover most if not
all who want it in cases where it would
be too risky or too expensive the
private insurance markets provide
solutions the government has stepped in
with the National Flood Insurance
Program run by Femina license their
agents and brokers insurance reps need
to know this business inside now Nass
contracts state laws regulations the
ABCs insurance yeah we know for the
public it's more like falling asleep we
live and breathe I live and breathe the
stuff and we passed the test to prove it
now when coming into retirement what is
good about insurance companies if you
look at your financial aspect of it I
want to share this little video that
stood at two minute video of how an
insurance company can give you a quick
of a portfolio value whoops I can find
my mouse there we go the process of
saving for retirement is commonly
understood save a certain amount each
year invest it and give your nest egg
time to grow but once you are ready to
retire and start living on that income
things can quickly become more confusing
if you spend any time on the internet
you will quickly discover that there are
many approaches to generating retirement
income to help you evaluate those
approaches a concept called
equivalent portfolio value or UPV can be
helpful
simply put epd evaluates how much income
one approach can generate versus another
and what it will take for two different
approaches to generate the same level of
income take the two siblings Marc and
Mary both spent their working years
saving for retirement they were planning
to retire in five years and each of them
had saved five hundred and fifty
thousand dollars after doing some math
both mark and Mary determined that they
would need forty thousand a year from
their savings to meet their retirement
income needs Marc decides to use a
drawdown approach while maintaining an
asset allocation strategy withdrawing
four percent annually based on his five
hundred and fifty thousand dollars today
four percent will only generate twenty
two thousand dollars just over half what
he needs in order to generate the forty
thousand dollars from his investment
plan his five hundred and fifty thousand
dollars will need to grow to 1 million
in five years for 82% alternatively Mary
decides to utilize a fixed index annuity
to generate the forty thousand dollars
the fixed indexed annuity guarantees
that it's Mary places five hundred and
five
$2,000 in it today in five years the
insurance company would begin paying her
$40,000 she needs each year for as long
as she lives to put it another way
Mary's five hundred and fifty thousand
dollars fixed index annuity has an EP D
of 1 million dollars by using a fixed
index annuity mary has peace of mind
that she will receive the income she
needs in retirement on the other hand in
order for mark to generate the level of
income he needs his drop down approach
would require his portfolio to earn an
annual rate of return of twelve point
seven two percent before fees and taxes
each and every year for the next five
years
only then will mark have the 1 million
dollars he needs for retirement
using epd can be useful to compare
retirement income approaches but how is
it that Mary's 550 thousand dollars can
do the work of 1 million it is because
Mary is tapping into one of the unique
strengths of insurance companies
insurance companies can pool risk across
tens of thousands of people with
insurance companies we can do more
together than we can alone mark on the
other hand must face the risks of
retirement all by himself if there is a
financial mishap he only has himself to
manage the impact of that setback so
how's your financial professional is a
fixed index annuity might be right for
you
I like that video just it shows that you
don't have to get greedy and you don't
have to make money in order to be able
to spend money so when we're talking
about insurance companies and we've been
doing that the last half hour or so I
mean if you look at the for the
generally for most important things that
everybody has in this world that they
wonder what because they have a car who
protects the car then you have your
family and loved ones and legacy who
protects them who protects yourself in
case you get sick and your home in case
something happens to that well love it
or not insurance companies are here to
protect you
yeah they're gonna make their money but
at the end of the day you're gonna make
your money back if something happens if
something happens your car to call the
insurance company you get sick you're
calling insurance company they're there
to protect yourself so if you're willing
to protect for the most important parts
your life your your car yourself to your
family in your home I ask yourself this
one thing before closing is why not
protect your financial portfolio in your
future with a insurance company as well
now I want to thank you for attending
from this presentation here and I hope
you learned a little bit about more
about insurance companies and hope you
get a little bit more positive outlook
that they're here at the end of the day
to protect you I mean there are a lot of
cons out there I'm here a cleric of
strategies group these are the resources
we offer which is on the attachment on
the right if you can pick those out
we're going to a website all this is
complimentary we don't charge you for
any of these resources whatsoever where
next week's webinar is on a baby boomer
basics it's a classic that's one of the
most detailed webinar so if you are a
baby boomer I highly encourage you to go
to this webinar if you don't want to
miss this one and you'd like to schedule
a time to talk with me one on one either
in person over the phone or my internet
you can go to county complex Dolf Janice
and schedule meeting at a time and
convenience that's convenient for you
you don't even need to give us a call
and so forth so again on behalf of our
team here clerk of strategies group I
want to thank you for listening to our
presentation today on the pros and cons
of insurance companies um please follow
us on Facebook or YouTube channels if we
can give you our monthly newsletters and
updates when we find things out of the
economy of what's happening one way or
the other and in the meantime thanks
again for joining us I wish everyone on
this call a wonderful and safe healthy
weekend stay safe out there from all the
craziness that's out there remember take
care of yourself and we'll take care of
others so everyone be safe hope to talk
to each one of you very soon and god
bless bye bye
you